[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：早上好，我是Doug Crockford。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So good morning, I'm Doug Crockford.
这是三天的好部分。
This is three days of the good parts.
出乎意料的是，JavaScript成为了，也许是最重要的编程
Unexpectedly, JavaScript has become, perhaps the most important programming
世界上最令人惊讶的语言，
language in the world, which is surprising,
因为它也是世界上最容易被误解的编程语言，
because it's also the world's most misunderstood programming language,
这周我们会试着解决一些问题。
which we'll try to fix some of that this week.
这就是课程的大纲。
So, this is the outline for the course.
今天将是一系列的五堂课，我对此表示歉意。
Today is going to be a series of five lectures and I apologize for that.
我需要给你很多信息
There's a lot of information I need to give you and
我知道的唯一方法就是说出来。
the only way I know to do that is to say it.
所以你得听我整天抱怨，但是
So you're gonna have to listen to me whining on all day, but
明天会更好。
tomorrow will be much better.
明天我们要去研讨会。
Tomorrow, we're gonna workshop.
我们会在函数上玩得很开心。
We're gonna have fun with functions.
你可以写程序，这会很棒的。
You could be writing programs and it's gonna be great.
明天我们会过得更好。
We're gonna have a much better time tomorrow.
然后在第三天，我们将做一些更有趣的函数，
Then on the third day, we'll do some more fun with functions,
然后我们也来看一些非常重要的话题。
then we'll also look at some very important topics.
安全性、异步性，这是您必须处理的许多问题，
Security, asynchronicity, which is something you have to deal on a lot with,
特别是在服务器和展望这种语言的未来的更好的部分中
especially in servers and the better parts looking at the future of this language and
其他语言，使之听起来令人愉快。
other languages So that sound agreeable.
所以，让我们从第一部分的编程风格和你的大脑开始。
So, let's begin with part one programming style and your brain.
这是两个似乎毫无关系的话题。
These are two topics which appear to have nothing to do with each other.
编程风格是编译器注意到的程序的一部分
Programming Style is the part of your program that the compiler notice and
有些人认为因为编译器不关心，
some people think that because the compiler doesn't care,
你不应该在意任何款式和其他款式一样好-这只是品味的问题。
you shouldn't care any styles as good as another it's just a matter of taste.
我会试着说服你不是这样的
I'm gonna try to persuade you that that is not the case,
有些风格明显优于其他风格，然后是你的大脑。
that some styles are significantly better than others and then your brain.
你的大脑就是你头骨里的那一大块肉，你用它来思考和思考
Your brain is that big wad of meat in your skull that you think with and
这两件事之间有什么可能的联系呢？
what possible connection could there be between these two things?
嗯，结果是有一种联系，一种令人惊讶而又重要的联系。
Well, turns out there is a connection, a surprising and important one.
我会歪曲丹尼尔·卡尼曼的工作
I'm gonna be misrepresenting the work of Daniel Kahneman,
诺贝尔奖获得者心理学家。
the Nobel Winning Psychologist.
现在，诺贝尔没有颁发心理学奖。
Now, Nobel does not give a prize for psychology.
所以他们给了他经济学奖，但他不是经济学家，但是
So they gave him the award for economics, but he's not an economist, but
他发现经济学的一个基本假设是站不住脚的。
he found that one of the fundamental assumptions of economics doesn't hold.
也就是说，在任何事务中，
That is that in any transaction,
可以期望一个政党追求自己的最佳利益。
a party can be expected to pursue their own best interests.
Kahneman表明，如果一个政党是一个人，则情况并非如此，
Kahneman shows this is not the case if a party is a human being,
因为人类的思维方式与经济学家的思维方式不同。
because human beings do not think the way economists think we think.
事实上，我们中没有人以我们认为我们思考的方式思考。
In fact, none of us think the way we think we think.
而且你越研究Kahneman
And the more you study Kahneman,
更令人惊讶的是，我们曾经做过任何事情。
the more amazing it is that we ever get anything done at all.
所以Kahneman有一个比喻
So Kahneman has a metaphor for
人类思想建立在两个系统相互作用的基础上。
human thought based on the interaction of two systems.
系统二和系统一。
System two and system one.
系统二，我们可以把它想象成头部，是更高层次的系统。
System two, which we can think of as the head is the higher level one.
这是分析性的。
It's analytic.
这是算法。
It's algorithmic.
这是我们做数学，推理和逻辑的地方。
It's where we do mathematics and reasoning, and logic.
这是一台非常精密的机器。
It's a really sophisticated machine.
它需要大量的努力才能使用，而且速度非常慢。
It requires a tremendous amount of effort to use and it is very slow.
所以，我们尽可能让它关闭。
So, we leave it turned off as much as possible.
这是因为这个系统太慢了，我们不得不发明计算机，
It's because that system is so slow that we had to invent computers,
因为系统二不能产生社会的所有数字
because system two is not capable of generating all of the numbers that society
为了做到这一点，需要社会进化。
needed in order to do it social evolution.
所以我们需要想出一些机器来进行这种处理
So we needed to come up with machines to do that processing for
我们，然后是系统一。
us, then there's system one.
系统一，你可以认为是你的直觉。
System one, you can think of as your gut.
这是直觉。
It is intuitive.
这是启发式的。
It's heuristic.
这是联想。
It's associative.
非常快。
It is very, very fast.
这不需要努力。
It requires no effort.
事实上，你无法关闭它。
And in fact, you cannot turn it off.
它一直在运行，我们有这两个系统的想法并不是新的。
It's on all the time and the idea that we have these two systems is not new.
我的意思是，我们都有这种直觉，我们有这两个系统
I mean, we all have this intuitive sense that we've got these two systems and
有时你甚至能听到他们。
sometimes you can even hear them.
有时如果你对重要的事情感到困惑，你可以听到你的
Sometimes if you're confused about something important, you can hear your
头脑告诉你一件事，你的直觉告诉你其他事情。
head telling you one thing and your gut telling you something else.
我们都经历过。
We've all experienced that.
Kahneman发现的是这两个系统是如何连接的。
What Kahneman found was how the two systems are connected.
它发现系统2得到了它的假设，它的赠与，
It turns up system two gets its assumptions, its givens,
其工作集来自系统一，且不知道该连接。
its working set from system one and is not aware of that connection.
系统二认为它是从深层真理的宝库中得到的东西，但是
System two thinks it's getting the stuff from the vault of deep truth, but
不是。
it's not.
它是从一号系统和一号系统得到的，
It's getting it from system one and system one,
因为它是一个近似的系统，有时会出错。
because it's an approximate system sometimes gets things wrong.
如果你有一个带有错误输入的逻辑系统，
And if you have a logical system with false inputs,
你可能会得到错误的输出，结果证明我们一直在这样做。
you can get false outputs and it turns out we do this all the time.